<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Education</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Education</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:23:47 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kylejones200.github.io/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Learned to Become a Better Writer</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/how-i-learned-to-become-a-better-writer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:23:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/how-i-learned-to-become-a-better-writer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Students have to produce written deliverables like essays, case analyses, and reports. While the technical content is important, the quality of our writing can make a big difference in how effectively we communicate our ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a recent class, the instructor shared some valuable writing tips that can help elevate our written work. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the key insights:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Get to the Point: When writing for a professional audience, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to use fancy, complex language. In fact, the simpler and more direct our writing, the better. Avoid overly formal or &amp;ldquo;Latinized&amp;rdquo; words in favor of plain, straightforward language. The goal is to convey your ideas clearly, not to impress with your vocabulary. Keep your sentences short and concise.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incorporate Data: Use data to support our points. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s financial figures, project metrics, or other relevant statistics, incorporating quantitative information can make our arguments more compelling and well-rounded. Present the data clearly and tie it back to your key points.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be Bold and Opinionated: New writers tend to hedge their statements. Instead, be clear on what you think. Take a stand and make your perspectives clear. You are being paid for your opinion. Share it confidently (and back it up with data).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check Your Readability: Make it easy to read. Use readability tools like the Hemingway App and Grammarly. These will analyze the grade level and complexity of our text and provide suggestions for simplifying sentences and improving flow. The Flesch-Kincaid readability score is built into MS Word and corresponds your text to a U.S. grade school level. Aim for a 6–8 grade reading level—the sweet spot for most professional communications.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>By keeping these tips in mind, we can elevate the quality of our written work and communicate our project management insights more effectively. The next time you sit down to draft a case analysis or report, remember to be direct, data-driven, bold, and easy to read. Good luck!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Communications Plan for Yourself</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/building-a-communications-plan-for-yourself/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/building-a-communications-plan-for-yourself/</guid><description>&lt;p>Growth in communication benefits from planning. A simple framework helps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ask yourself: Where am I now? Where do I want to be? Who is my audience? What tools do I need? How will I measure progress?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A student might want to improve essays, interviews, or class talks. The tools could be practice sessions, coaching, or feedback. Progress shows through clearer writing, stronger delivery, and more confidence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With a plan, improvement is steady and measurable. Communication becomes a skill you build, not a trait you accept.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Going to School While Working Full Time</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/going-to-school-while-working-full-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/going-to-school-while-working-full-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many employers provide the opportunity to continue my education with support from the company.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved school and had been dreaming of returning to school from the day after my graduation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started an online degree program in 2015 and learned the hard way some of the limitations that come with this business.  I&amp;rsquo;m not in HR and I can&amp;rsquo;t speak for them but I wanted to share my experience in hope that you can avoid some of my mistakes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Know Your Audience</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/know-your-audience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/know-your-audience/</guid><description>&lt;p>Strong communicators start with the audience. Who are you addressing? What do they know already? What do they expect from you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Admissions officers read thousands of essays each year. They look for genuine voice, not inflated language. Professors expect depth and clarity. Recruiters value confidence and focus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One framework divides audiences into four groups: supportive, neutral, skeptical, and resistant. Each group requires a different emphasis. Supportive listeners respond to affirmation. Neutral ones want clarity. Skeptical audiences want evidence. Resistant audiences expect respect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Message, Delivery, and Follow-Up</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/message-delivery-and-follow-up/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/message-delivery-and-follow-up/</guid><description>&lt;p>Effective communication has three dimensions. The first is the message—the core idea you want to share. The second is delivery—the style, tone, and medium. The third is follow-up—the way you reinforce the message over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A student writing a personal statement may focus on resilience. That theme can reappear in an interview and again in a recommendation letter. Consistency across settings makes the message stronger and more memorable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linking what you say, how you say it, and how you sustain it creates communication that lasts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking with Confidence</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/speaking-with-confidence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/speaking-with-confidence/</guid><description>&lt;p>Public speaking feels intimidating to many students. The best way to grow is through practice. Rehearse in safe settings such as a debate club, a class presentation, or a mock interview. Record yourself and watch for clarity, pace, and presence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Structure your talk clearly. Begin with an introduction, build through the main points, and end with a firm conclusion. Limit yourself to one or two central ideas so the audience stays with you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Power of Story</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/the-power-of-story/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/the-power-of-story/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stories transform abstract ideas into real experiences. They bring life to facts and figures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>College essays resonate more when they tell a story. A student who wants to show resilience can share a moment when persistence mattered. Presentations gain strength when they weave examples into the argument.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Organizations use stories to define their culture. Students can use them to define themselves. A personal story about service, discovery, or growth makes a message memorable and genuine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Communication Matters</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/why-communication-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/why-communication-matters/</guid><description>&lt;p>Communication shapes every part of a student’s education. Colleges want applicants who can write with clarity, speak with confidence, and connect with people. Grades and test scores open the door, but words and presence are what leave an impression.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good communication goes beyond information. It builds connection. People may forget the details of what you said, but they remember how you made them feel. An essay that sounds honest and grounded carries weight. A presentation delivered with poise earns trust.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing with Clarity</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/writing-with-clarity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/writing-with-clarity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Writing well is a cornerstone of success in college and beyond. Essays, research papers, and emails all demand precision and clarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The strongest writing is direct. Say what you mean. Cut unnecessary words. Revise until each sentence works. Samuel Johnson once said, “What is written without effort is read without pleasure.” Clear prose requires care.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Different platforms call for different approaches. Essays need structure. Social media posts need brevity. Video scripts need rhythm. In every case, the goal remains the same: clarity and connection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advanced Placement, CLEP, and Sophia Credits</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/advanced-placement-clep-and-sophia-credits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/advanced-placement-clep-and-sophia-credits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many students assume they must wait until May to take Advanced Placement (AP) exams. In reality, credit can come from multiple sources and at different times. CLEP exams, for example, allow students to test out of introductory courses year-round. Online platforms such as Sophia.org offer self-paced courses in dozens of subjects, and completion can translate into transferable credit at many universities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sophia currently covers around eighty lower-division subjects. Some students complete multiple courses in a single month, taking advantage of the flexibility. Learn.org provides another route, sometimes offering credit at the upper-division level. These options can save time and money, particularly at institutions that are generous in awarding transfer credit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Architecture Programs in the U.S.</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/architecture-programs-in-the-us/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/architecture-programs-in-the-us/</guid><description>&lt;p>Students pursuing architecture face two distinct educational paths. The first is the professional track, which leads directly to licensure. This typically takes the form of a five-year Bachelor of Architecture (B.Arch) degree. Programs on this track are tightly structured, with little room for electives. Students spend long hours in studios and labs, completing a sequence designed to prepare them fully for the licensing process. Schools such as the &lt;a href="https://www.ou.edu/">University of Oklahoma&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.k-state.edu/">Kansas State University&lt;/a> offer this model, often requiring summer coursework to fit everything into five years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Claremont Colleges</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/claremont-colleges/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/claremont-colleges/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="claremont-colleges">Claremont Colleges&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.claremont.edu/">Claremont Colleges&lt;/a> in Southern California form one of the most distinctive higher education consortia in the United States. Instead of one large university, the consortium consists of several small, highly selective colleges, each with its own character. Students apply to one—&lt;a href="https://www.pomona.edu/">Pomona&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.cmc.edu/">Claremont McKenna&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.hmc.edu/">Harvey Mudd&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.scrippscollege.edu/">Scripps&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://www.pitzer.edu/">Pitzer&lt;/a>—but once enrolled, they can take classes across the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Academically, this provides remarkable breadth. A Harvey Mudd student focused on engineering can enroll in a Pomona philosophy course. A Claremont McKenna political science major can take a science class at Pitzer. Each college has its own admissions rate, culture, and traditions, but they share libraries, athletic teams, and cross-registration. From the student perspective, the boundaries blur quickly, and life feels like one large community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Columbia and Barnard in NYC</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/columbia-and-barnard-in-nyc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/columbia-and-barnard-in-nyc/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.columbia.edu/">Columbia University&lt;/a> offers a different model of New York education. Columbia sits in Morningside Heights, with a classic quadrangle and clear campus boundaries. It feels self-contained, even though the city presses in on every side. Columbia has its own distinctive culture of rigorous academics and international prestige. Alongside it stands &lt;a href="https://barnard.edu/">Barnard College&lt;/a>, a women’s college that maintains its independence while sharing resources with Columbia. Barnard students can take classes across the street, use Columbia’s libraries, and graduate with a Columbia degree while also belonging to Barnard’s more intimate environment. This partnership provides the best of both worlds: the community of a small women’s college and the reach of an Ivy League university.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cooper Union</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/cooper-union/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/cooper-union/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cooper.edu/">Cooper Union&lt;/a> in New York City was founded with the idea that higher education should be free. For most of its history, students paid no tuition. In recent years, financial pressures forced the school to introduce tuition, but its leadership remains committed to returning to a tuition-free model. That mission still shapes the culture of the institution. Students at Cooper Union are admitted into highly selective programs in art, architecture, and engineering. The admissions process is rigorous, often involving portfolios, exams, and interviews that measure creativity as well as academic strength.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dishing on Graduate Schools in Policy and International Affairs</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/dishing-on-graduate-schools-in-policy-and-international-affairs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/dishing-on-graduate-schools-in-policy-and-international-affairs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Choosing a graduate school in public policy or international affairs is not simple. Each program has its strengths and weaknesses, and much depends on what a student values: academic rigor, professional networking, financial aid, or location. Here are impressions of some of the leading schools, drawn from firsthand experience and conversations with friends and colleagues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="harvard-kennedy-school">&lt;a href="https://www.hks.harvard.edu/">Harvard Kennedy School&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Kennedy School carries prestige, but it comes with tradeoffs. Its first year is heavy on core requirements, more so than most peers. Students spend much of that year in large lecture halls with 50 to 100 classmates. Not every professor excels at teaching, and not every student stands out as a star. But the payoff is exposure to a remarkable mix of people and ideas. High-profile visitors are a regular occurrence. During my two years, I saw at least ten heads of state. The network and the global connections make the Kennedy School hard to match, even if the day-to-day classroom experience can feel uneven.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do Grades Matter?</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/do-grades-matter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/do-grades-matter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Grades matter, but not always in the ways students expect. A high GPA can open doors, especially at the most selective colleges. But admissions committees review thousands of transcripts and rarely know the fine details of each school’s grading policies. A 3.8 from one high school may reflect much harder grading than a 4.0 from another. Reviewers do not usually parse those nuances. They see numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This reality is reinforced by rankings like &lt;em>U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report&lt;/em>. Colleges chase high average GPAs and test scores to rise in the rankings. As a result, admissions processes often treat a GPA as a standardized metric, even though it isn’t. A student at a school known for “grade deflation,” such as Wake Forest, might assume admissions officers will understand the difference. In practice, most don’t. They see a 3.5 next to someone else’s 3.9 and draw conclusions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gap Years and Deferrals</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/gap-years-and-deferrals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/gap-years-and-deferrals/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="gap-years-and-deferrals">Gap Years and Deferrals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An admissions officer at Princeton once explained that his top advice for students was simple: defer. Take a year between high school and college to gain experiences, learn about yourself, and build perspective. Colleges increasingly recognize the value of gap years. They understand that students who arrive after meaningful experiences—whether travel, service, work, or study abroad—often contribute more to the classroom and the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A gap year is not a year off; it is a year on a different track. Some students work to save money, gaining independence and maturity. Others travel, volunteer, or join structured programs abroad. The common theme is that they return with stories, insights, and resilience that enrich their college years. Admissions officers know this, which is why many encourage students to apply, gain admission, and then request a deferral.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Outward Bound and NOLS</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/special_programs/outward-bound-and-nols/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/special_programs/outward-bound-and-nols/</guid><description>&lt;p>Programs like &lt;a href="https://www.outwardbound.org/">Outward Bound&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://nols.edu/">National Outdoor Leadership School (NOLS)&lt;/a> offer something different from traditional education. They combine adventure, challenge, and personal growth in outdoor settings. Students can enroll in short courses, semester-long programs, or even earn college credit. The credit often falls under outdoor leadership or recreation studies, which may not transfer neatly into other majors. The deeper value lies not in the transcript but in the personal transformation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outward Bound has long fought a misconception that it serves primarily troubled youth. While a small percentage of participants attend under those circumstances, most enroll by choice, seeking adventure and growth. Instructors stress that fewer than 20 percent of students are there involuntarily. The majority want to test themselves in wilderness environments, build confidence, and develop teamwork skills. Students climb mountains, paddle rivers, and learn survival skills while confronting the limits of their comfort zones.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Public Policy and International Affairs Fellowship (PPIA)</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/special_programs/ppia-public-policy-and-international-affairs-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/special_programs/ppia-public-policy-and-international-affairs-fellowship/</guid><description>&lt;p>For students interested in government, international affairs, or public service, the &lt;a href="https://www.ppiaprogram.org/">Public Policy and International Affairs (PPIA) Fellowship&lt;/a> provides a pathway into graduate study. This program selects rising juniors from across the country and immerses them in an intensive summer of policy training. Host campuses include &lt;a href="https://www.princeton.edu/">Princeton&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.umich.edu/">University of Michigan&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.berkeley.edu/">UC Berkeley&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The curriculum mirrors what first-year master’s students encounter at leading schools of public policy. Participants take graduate-level coursework in statistics, economics, and policy analysis. They also work on real projects, applying theory to pressing issues such as healthcare reform or environmental regulation. The program is free for accepted students, removing financial barriers and broadening access to policy education.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Researching Colleges: Beyond the Rankings</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/researching-colleges-beyond-the-rankings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/researching-colleges-beyond-the-rankings/</guid><description>&lt;p>When families first start looking at colleges, they often turn to rankings or glossy brochures. Those resources provide some useful information, but they miss what really matters: the lived experience of students and the fit for each individual. My own journey into this work began after reading Loren Pope’s book &lt;em>Colleges That Change Lives&lt;/em>. The book highlighted smaller schools that shaped students in transformative ways. I looked for a more recent version and found there wasn’t one, so I began doing my own research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ROTC and Other Military Options</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/rotc-and-other-military-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/rotc-and-other-military-options/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not every student with an interest in military service chooses a service academy. Reserve Officers’ Training Corps (ROTC) programs provide another route. ROTC is offered at hundreds of universities, from large state schools to smaller private colleges. Students enroll in regular degree programs while also participating in military training, leadership courses, and summer field experiences. In exchange for this commitment, ROTC scholarships often cover tuition and provide stipends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ROTC students graduate with both a college degree and a commission as an officer in the armed forces. This flexibility appeals to students who want the full college experience but also value the structure and career path that military service offers. They can join student clubs, pursue internships, and major in any field, while also preparing for leadership in the &lt;a href="https://www.goarmy.com/rotc.html">Army ROTC&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.nrotc.navy.mil/">Navy ROTC&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://www.afrotc.com/">Air Force ROTC&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Service Academies</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/service-academies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/schools/service-academies/</guid><description>&lt;p>The U.S. service academies—&lt;a href="https://www.westpoint.edu/">West Point&lt;/a> (United States Military Academy), the &lt;a href="https://www.usna.edu/">Naval Academy&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.usafa.edu/">Air Force Academy&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.uscga.edu/">Coast Guard Academy&lt;/a>, and the &lt;a href="https://www.usmma.edu/">Merchant Marine Academy&lt;/a>—offer some of the most selective and distinctive college experiences in the country. Admission requires more than high test scores. Each candidate must secure a nomination from a U.S. senator, a representative, or in some cases the Vice President. These nominations are competitive and often involve their own applications, interviews, or evaluations. Students who hope to attend must begin preparing early in high school.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtual Internships (Smithsonian and Beyond)</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/virtual-internships-smithsonian-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/virtual-internships-smithsonian-and-beyond/</guid><description>&lt;p>Internships are an essential part of preparing for college and careers, but many students assume they must live in Washington, D.C., New York, or another major city to gain access. Virtual internships change that equation. Today, organizations such as the &lt;a href="https://www.si.edu/">Smithsonian&lt;/a> offer remote &lt;a href="https://intern.si.edu/">internship opportunities&lt;/a> that allow high school and college students to participate from anywhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What students actually do in a virtual internship varies. At the Smithsonian, for example, interns may help organize digital collections, contribute to online exhibitions, or support research projects. Other organizations might assign policy research, data analysis, or communications tasks. While not every project carries the prestige of walking through a famous museum each morning, the skills developed are real: time management, communication with supervisors, and the ability to contribute to professional work without face-to-face oversight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing College Essays</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/writing-college-essays/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/communications/writing-college-essays/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many students underestimate the importance of rewriting. They draft an essay, polish the grammar, and submit it. Admissions officers, however, can tell the difference between a first draft and a thoughtful, reworked piece. Strong essays usually emerge only after two or three complete rewrites. The process takes time, but it is the clearest path to an authentic and polished result.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When approaching the essay, students should begin by writing freely. The first draft should capture ideas without worrying about structure. That draft is then set aside. On the second attempt, students focus on clarity and flow, trimming unnecessary words and sharpening the point. A third draft should polish details, strengthen transitions, and ensure the essay reflects the applicant’s voice. At each stage, the student gets closer to an essay that is both personal and professional.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fellowships for Students of Public Policy and International Relations</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/scholarships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/scholarships/</guid><description>&lt;p>Introduction to Fellowships in Public Policy and International Relations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fellowships are the Eurail passes of a public policy career. They open doors, let you cover more ground, and connect you with fellow travelers headed in the same direction. Where scholarships mostly pay tuition, fellowships often add structure: summer institutes, mentoring, internships, and a network that sticks with you long after graduation. If scholarships are like free meals on the road, fellowships are like finding a host family that also teaches you how to cook.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Page not found</title><link>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/404/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kylejones200.github.io/education/404/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="404--page-not-found">404 — Page not found&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Sorry, we couldn’t find the page you were looking for.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Return to the &lt;a href="https://kylejones200.github.io/education/">home page&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Visit the &lt;a href="https://kylejones200.github.io/education/about/">About&lt;/a> page&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>